So let's implement this
Bu yzden bunu uygulayalm.
checkout component. I'll actually implement it in a container because it will be a component which
Check out bileeni gerekte bir konteyner olarak uygulanmaktadr nk bu bileen kendi durumunu
manages its own state and also passes this down to other components.
yneten ve ayrca Avro bileenlerine aktaran bir bileen olacaktr.
So add a new folder in containers and I'll name it checkout and in there I'll add that checkout.js
Bylece, kaplara yeni bir klasr ekleyin ve deme adn vereceim ve orada check it out'u ekleyeceim.
file which well should hold my checkout component.
JS dosyas da benim kontrol bileenimi tutmaldr.
It'll be a class based component and state will be involved and therefore I extend the component object
Snf temelli bileenler olacak ve devlet iin iine girecek ve bu nedenle, X'le
which I have to import from react together with the react package itself to support jsx.
desteklemek iin yeniden hareket paketi ile Gabr'a tepki olarak almak zorunda olduum bileen nesnesini geniletiyorum. Bu snf ekleyelim.
So let's add this class,
bileen parmak izini kontrol etmeyi planlayalm.
let's then export it as a default of this file and then let's plan how does it checkout component should
Daha sonra bunu varsaylan bir ofis dosyas olarak da aktaralm ve ardndan nasl yaplaca gibi
look like and should behave.
deme bileeninde sahip olmak istediiniz ey, kasann kk bir zetidir.
What I want to have in the checkout component is a tiny summary of the checkout
Dolaysyla temelde kullancnn satn almak zeresiniz ve fiyat muhtemelen ve daha sonra bir deme ilemini iptal
so basically what the user is about to buy and the price probably and then a button to cancel the checkout
etmek ve Bergere Boulder'e ve tabii ki devam etmek iin bir dmeye gitmek iin bir dme.
process and go back to the burger builder and of course a button to continue.
Ve zet olarak, malzemelerin sadece bir listesini
And I guess for the summary, it would be nice to not again show just a list of the ingredients but maybe
tekrar gstermemek, belki burgerin kendisini gstermek gzel olurdu sanrm.
show the burger itself,
Burgerini yeniden ina et.
rebuild the burger in this
zeti kontrol et.
checkout summary.
te Chaudiere zeti burada.
So that's the goal here, show this summary
Ve sonra kullanc devam etmeye tkladnda iletiim formunu yklemek istemiyorum.
and then when the user clicks on continue I then want to load the contact form.
Bu nedenle, adm adm adm hamburgerin bir nizlemesini grntlememe izin veren
So step by step, the goal therefore is to create a checkout summary form which allows me to display a
bir emir zet formu oluturmak ve devam etmek veya Tamam dmelerini iptal ettiklerim iin
preview of the burger and show the continue or cancel buttons. For that I'll go into my components folder
hepsi benim bileenler klasrne gidip yeni bir klasr eklemek iin adm adm hazrlamaktr.
and add a new folder in there
Adnz ne.
which I'll name
Kontrol edin
checkout or maybe order to replace all order related components there like the checkout component, check
ya da belki tm siparile ilgili bileenlerin bileen kontroln kontrol etmek gibi yerlerine yerletirilmesini emredin.
out
Adlandrlmaldr.
it should be named
zet belki kontrol edin.
checkout summary maybe.
Sonra da zet bir inceleme hazrlayn.
And then there I'll create a checkoutsummary
J. S. iine dmek.
.js file and a
zeti CSSA'nn stil iin dtn kontrol edin.
checkout summary css file for the styling.
imdi kontrol zet bileeni oluturmak iin fonksiyonel
Now let's have a look at the checkoutsummary.js file, there I'll use the functional form to
formu iin kullanlan hepsi zet dodgiest sonbahar gz atalm.
create the checkout summary component
Yani aslinda bildigin gibi burada Samari'nin fonksiyonunu kontrol et.
so basically just checkout summary function here as you know it.
Muhtemelen burgeri ilemek iin baz sahne alacak ve sonra baz GSX iade edecektir.
We will probably receive some props to render the burger and then return some jsx
Dolaysyla bu nedenle kesinlikle Riak paketinden yeniden aktarmaya ihtiyacmz var.
so therefore we definitely need to import react from the react package
Ve elbette her zaman da aktarr.
and of course as always, export
zeti varsaylan olarak kontrol edin.
checkout summary as the default.
imdi ama, tm ya da burger yllarnn bir nizlemesini grntlemek ve daha sonra devam etmek veya ptal dmelerini gstermektir.
Now the goal is to display a preview of our burger here and then show continue or cancel buttons.
Bu yzden ne yapacam J'de X'i istiyorum, hepsini ilk nce Raptor'un bir div'da
So what I'll do is in the jsx which I want to return here, I'll first of all wrap this in a div which
bulacam ve bu stil de baz stilde sylemek iin ekillendirme amacyla kullanacam.
I'll also use for styling purposes to give this component some style,
O zaman tadna bakmak istediini sylediim her bir etiketin olmasn istiyorum.
then I want to have a h1 tag where I say we hope it tastes well,
Byle bir ey ve teklifleri.
something like that and thereafter,
imdi temelde Bergere bileenimi nizlemek istediim bir div'da bir kutu istiyorum.
now I want to have a box, a div basically, where I want to preview my burger component.
Davis, Bergere bileeninin snrlarn belirlemeyi ister mi?
This div is required to set the boundaries of that burger component.
Elbette, sahip olduum Bergere bileenini tekrar kullanacam.
and of course I'm going to reuse my burger component which I already have,
Bu harika ey bu.
that's the cool thing,
Yeniden kullanabiliriz,
we can reuse it. So I'll set some inline styling here on that wrapping div which will hold my burger
bylece burada, 300 piksel tasarruf geniliini ayarlamak iin burger tutacak ve sonra da 300 piksel
just to set the width of let's say 300px and then also our height of let's say 300px and let's
diyelim ykseklii ayarlayacak olan sarg divunda baz satr ii stil ayarlayacaz ve sonra da kenar boluunu buraya gel.
then also set the margin to auto here.
imdi div'n burger bileenlerini yalnzca Bergere'yi tmyle ie aktarmak
Now inside that div I want to use my burger component, I'll import it. I'll import burger from and
ve Bergere klasrne gitmek ve imdi de Steve J'yi dosya olarak kullanmak istiyorum.
now navigate up into the burger folder and there is the burger.js file,
imdi rahatlkla ekleyebildiim saat olan Bergere bileeni byle mi iliyor.
this is our burger component which I can now conveniently add like this,
Burger kendini kapatan bir etiket.
the burger, a self-closing tag.
Ben de ieriklerimi babama geirmem gerek.
I there also need to pass my ingredients and for that
Elbette bu maddeleri nasl aldm bilmek nemlidir.
it will of course be important to know how I receive these ingredients.
imdilik burger bileeninin maddeler zelliini yalnzca
I assume that for now I can simply just set the ingredients property of my burger component which it
burger bileenine bakarsak bekledii ekilde ayarlayabilirim varsayyorum.
does expect if we have a look at the burger component,
Kullandmz pervane malzemesi var,
we have props ingredients in there which we use so I should also pass this to this ingredient, to this
bu yzden gemi herey bugnk Tudor bileenindeki bileeni olmal.
component
Belki zet bir zet kontrol etmeyin veya yapmayn.
Oops not ordersummary, checkoutsummary,
Buradayz.
here we are.
Dolaysyla biberonun
So we expect the ingredients in the burger so we should pass it and for now I'll just expect that in the
ierdii malzemeleri bekleyelim, bu yzden bunu gemeliyiz ve imdilik sadece deme zet bileeninde bekliyoruz.
checkout summary component,
istemediim maddeler mlkiyetini
I'll also get ingredients property which I then just pass on. Below that I then want to show my buttons
alacam Muhtemelen bildiiniz gibi dme tabii ki der ve DS dmeleri iki farkl stili destekler.
and for that, i'll import my own buttons I built. So the button component from the UI folder and there
Ayrca, daha sonra yalnzca aadaki dmeleri gstermek istemiyorum ve hepsi bu dme bileenini UI
from the button folder and then the button.js file of course and these buttons as you probably know support
klasrnden ve orada dme klasrnden ina etmi olduum tm kendi ie aktarmalar gze almam
two different styles,
Baarmz var
we have the success and the danger class here which we can pass and we do pass it with the button type
ve geemediimiz tehlike snf var ve dme tipi zelliklerle geiyoruz.
property.
Bu yzden dmelerimi aada ekleyeceim.
So I'll add my buttons below
lk dmede var.
there, I'll add the first button
Dme trnn baka yeri.
where I'll set the button type to
Byk bir tehlike ile tehlike diyelim, nk FCC, R sadece silmek istediklerini sylemek isteyen bir snf ad tayor.
let's say Danger with a capital D because that's the css class name where I is simply want to say CANCEL,
Belki tm kapaklar sadece durdurma amacyla kullandm ve daha sonra sahip olduum
maybe all caps for styling purposes only and then I'll duplicate it to also have a Success button with
her eye oaldm diyerek eriebileceim bir S harfi ile devam etmesini syleyeceim.
a capital S where I will say CONTINUE.
Yani bunlar iki dme.
So these are the two buttons,
Dmelerin tklama zelliini ortaya
you also know that the buttons expose the click property which simply indicates that we clicked on the
koyduunu da biliyorsunuz ki bu butona tkladmz gsteriyor, bu da hepimizin yapmas gereken bir ey.
button, so that is something I'll also need to do,
Bunu birden fazla satra blelim.
let's split this over multiple lines,
Uygulama buraya tkladktan sonra bir tklama ile bir eyler yapyor.
implement click here and then do something upon a click.
imdilik ekleyeceim bir ey bu bileenin stilini bitirmek istiyorum.
Now that is something I will add, for now I just want to finish the styling of this component.
Bu nedenle, zet JSA X kodumuzdaki eklerimizi aldk.
So with that we got our checkout summary jsx code,
imdi de sarmalayan div'a bir snf ad atamama izin verin ve bu,
now let me also assign a class name to the wrapping div and this is a class I want to set up in check
kurmak istediiniz bir snftr ve zeti zetlemek iin zetini inceleyin, i snfn buradan grn.
outsummary.css file. I'll add the checkoutsummary css class here
nk biz tekrar ders projemize girdiimizi hatrlyoruz, CSSA modllerini burada stilimizi kapsamaya koyuyoruz.
because remember we're back in our course project, we're using css modules here to scope our styles.
Bunlarn hepsi ortalamann her yerine ortalamak zere hizalanr veya genilii belki yzde
There I'll set text align to center to center everything, I'll set the width to 80% maybe and
80'e, otomatik kenar boluuna ayarlarsa Centre div yapar veya eleman yapar.
a margin of auto to then center this div or this element
Ayrca bir medya sorgusu ekleyeceim, en az 600 piksele
and I'll add a media query where I'll check if we have a minimum width of 600px at which point of time
sahip olup olmadm kontrol ediyorum, hangi noktada genilii snrlamak istemiyorum ki artk yzde deil.
I simply want to limit the width so that it's no longer a percent
Ancak burada 500 piksel ile snrlandracam.
but here I will limit it to 500px
imdi ithal etmek zorunda olduum, kod veya
Now with that I have to import this css code or the classes object you should be precise, from
snf nesnesi olarak zet C S S'ye gz atp tam olarak burada olmas gerektii anlamna geliyor.
checkoutsummary.css and then assign it here.
Yani burada herkes snflar ekliyor.
So here I'll add classes
zeti kontrol et.
checkout summary
C S S modllerinden faydalanarak burada.
taking advantage of css modules here.
imdi zet bileenini kontrol edeceiz.
Now we get to checkoutsummary component,
klasrnden oluturduum zet bileenini ieri aktaracam.
I now want to use that in my checkout file, in my checkout container to be precise. So there, I'll quickly
Kontrol dosyamdaki stat' ne zaman kullanacam biliyorum, konteyneri kontrol etmek iin kesin olmas iin, hzl bir ekilde bileen
import that checkoutsummary component we just created from the components folder
Bu nedenle, zet klasrne gz atan sipari klasr
therefore, there I created that order folder which hold the checkout summary folder and there, the check
oluturdum ve zet Ejay'yi dosya olarak kontrol ettim.
outsummary.js file.
imdi nereden ben bir tabaka dndren
Now inside my checkout component where I'll implement a render method where I then of course return
bir render yntemi uygulayacam bileeni imdi iinde orada GSX duyuyorum dndrr Bu bir re-act ynlendirici ile bir sayfa
some jsx, there I want to have a div which wraps my entire page because this will be used as a page with
olarak kullanlacak nk benim tm sayfay saran bir div istiyorum elbette ve hepsi imdi de.
the react router of course and in there, I'll now add
Bunun gibi zetlere gz atn.
checkoutsummary like this.
Aklnda tut.
Keep in mind,
zeti kontrol
checkoutsummary expects to get ingredients as a prop so I should pass ingredients here and that of
edin, bylece malzemeyi bir pervane olarak almasn bekliyor, bylece malzemeler burada iletmeli ve bu tabii ki ilgin bir sorudur.
course is an interesting question,
Malzemelerimi nereden bulabilirim.
where do I get my ingredients from?
imdilik, yalnzca bir kukla ierik nesnesini geeceim, ancak elbette bunun yerini alacam bir ey.
For now, I'll simply pass a dummy ingredients object but of course this is something I will replace.
deme unsuruna devlet ekleyeceim ve u an iin katk maddeleri
I will add state to the checkout component and there in the state, I'll add ingredients and ingredients
ilave edeceim durumda bir et peynir ve domuz pastrmas salatas olacak.
for now will be salad one, meat one, cheese one and bacon one
Ve bu yine, deitirdiim baz kukla veri.
and this again is just some dummy data which I'll replace.
malzemeyi yeniden pskrtmek iin rotay kullanmamz gerekecek.
So for now that allows me to pass this.state.ingredients, we will have to use routing to really pass ingredients
Bu yzden u an iin bu devlet maddelerini gememe izin veriyor, daha sonra
later.
imdi yaz aylarnda kontrolden kp konteyneri kontrol etmeye alyoruz.
Now we get the checkoutsummary and checkout container here,
Tabii ki bunu kullanmak istiyorum biliyorum
I now want to use it of course and for that, I will hardcode it into my app.js file right below the
ve bu nedenle, benim houma giden Cheras'mn Bergere Boulder'n tam altna deceim.
burger builder.
te ithalat
Here I'll import the checkout container from ./Containers/Checkout/Checkout just to see how
ama konteyner gz atn nokta kontur konteyner gzetlemek sadece nasl grndn grmek iin.
it looks.
Yaknda ykleyeceiz ve kablolamayacaz.
We will load and wire routing soon,
Tm dosyalar kaydettiinizden ve NPM balatma ileminin altndan ve sayfanzla birlikte olmanz durumunda sunduundan emin olun.
make sure to save all files and make sure npm start is running and thereafter, if you visit your page,
Tklama sesi dinleyicisi ile ilgili bir hata aldk, ancak u anda sorun olmamal.
We get an error regarding the onclick listener but that shouldn't be a problem right now.
Bizim gibi grnyor.
This is how it looks like our
zet bileenini kontrol edin.
checkoutsummary component.
imdi bence bir ekilde
Now we can see that somehow the state of the burger is not really centered so this is something we
burgerle birlikte durmak gerekten ortalanmamaktadr, bu yzden dzeltmemiz gereken bir eydir.
should fix.
Bunun iin, burgeri nerede kullandmn
For that, I'll go back into the checkoutsummary where I used the burger and one thing I should adjust here
zetini kontrol etmeye geri dneceim ve burada ayarlamam gereken bir ey, kontrol zet bileeninin tam geniliini almak iin% 100 ile ne kullanmam gerektiidir.
is that I should use width 100% to take the full width of the checkout summary component.
Artk bununla birlikte hem kk hem de byk cihazlarda imdi daha iyi grnyor ve daha kk grnyor.
Now with that that looks much better on both small devices and bigger devices. Now on small devices
Geen sene biraz daha ykseklik kazandk.
here, we got a little bit much height,
Bunu, bu ykseklii devre d brakarak dzeltebileceimiz bir ey yapar.
this is something we can fix by disabling this height,
Her zaman bo piksel olarak ayarlanmamas.
to not always setting it to 300px.
Diyelim ki burada gizlilik zelliinden kurtulalm.
So let's just get rid of the height property here too,
Biraz fazla stil iin.
for the styling that was a little bit too much.
imdi bunu mobil cihazlarda ve masastnde kesinlikle kullanabiliriz.
Now we can definitely use that on mobile devices and on the desktop,
Bu iyi grnyor.
this looks good
yerine gsterilmelidir.
too. Now of course there is still some space but we need some space for bigger burgers so this is deliberate
Q Artk elbette biraz boluk var ama daha byk Burger iin biraz bo alana ihtiyacmz var ki, zgrletirmek de
but the main thing I now want to work on is that I don't always display this but instead this should
yle. Fakat imdi zerinde almak istediim ana ey u ki bunu her zaman grntlemem ama bunun
be displayed.
Sipari zerine tklarsam imdi devam ederseniz, burger oluturucu yerine zetini kontrol etmek iin yklemek isterim.
If I click on order now, continue then I want to load to checkoutsummary instead of the burger builder,
Dats ama ve tabii ki veri iin ynlendirme gerekir.
that's the goal and for that of course we need routing.
imdi ekinmekten ekinmeyin ve bunu kendi
Now feel free to go ahead and implement this on your own and then compare your solution with mine which
banza uygulayn ve daha sonraki dersinde bina yapmaya balayacanz kendi zmnz benimle karlatrn.